There are some tokens that will never
recover because they are piece of
tokens.
>> The famous four-year cycle is dead.
>> The peaks of each of those all-time high
was in Q4 of 13,1 17 and 21. Now
obviously people are saying oh it's Q4
of 2025. So maybe now is the top. The
question is does that apply in this 4ear
cycle? And I think we're going to
massive money printing all over the
world and sometime the end of the decade
we'll get a massive bare market and
everything. And that tells me that this
4ear cycle is uh not going to happen
that we'll extend it. along
>> year-to- date silver, gold, and a lot of
tech stock outperforming Bitcoin. While
we are sitting here talking about
Bitcoin being the best performing asset
in the world that was not quite the
altcoin season we were expecting
>> that 99.99% of all these things are
zeros,
>> big liquidations. Do you think it is
just how leverage work in a very thin
market? Does it reveal something that is
broken in the system? What happened?
>> There were rules. People didn't read the
rules. You need to take a little bit
longer term view on what you're buying
so that you're not sitting there trying
to you can jive in the markets and
getting chopped up and liquidated and
all those things because you can't
concentrate to the level necessary to be
successful as a trader who uses
leverage. People have a dream but they
don't think about the time that they
want to invest to get there. And that's
the unfortunate part. I can't go give a
You are not all Michael Sailor.
Trump thinks that the stock market and
the crypto market are his report card.
How well is he doing? What's the S&P?
What's Bitcoin now? Bitcoin a million
dollars. It's very simple. Like
everything's up. S&P 10,000, NASDAQ
50,000
[Music]
>> stacking crypto like it's her claim to
fame. If you want success, then take a
look away.
>> Okay, ladies and gentlemen, today's
guest, Arthur Hayes, he is one of my
favorite people in the world to listen
to. He is the CIO of Maelstrom and
inventor of perpetual contract and a
writer that the whole industry just
reads. And most importantly, he is the
lord of the memes.
>> Thank you.
>> So good to have you back.
>> Thanks for having me.
>> Let's start with this. You you love
skiing. You love tennis, lifting, and
running. And you said you do those
things 3 hours a day
>> pretty much. Yeah. And it sounds fun and
all, but that takes a lot of discipline.
>> I love sports. I've always loved being
an athlete. So, it's awesome that I have
the ability to spend my time doing
things that I like doing.
>> So, it was never like, "Oh my god, I
don't want to move today. I just want to
be in bed, but I have to."
>> No, I love doing it. Like, I love being
out in the mountain for 8 hours a day.
Like, I couldn't think of anything else
I'd want to do. I think you have this
superpower that most people see the
world in different fragments like the
Fed, China, US, um, crypto market, but
you somehow you connect them all and you
make really complex things very simple.
So, I'd love for you to break it down
for us. The biggest picture of all, the
famous four-year cycle is dead, you
said.
>> Yeah. And so I presented a three
different scenarios or time periods.
2009 to 2013, 2013 to 2017, 2017 to
2021. And as everyone knows or don't
know, essentially the peaks of each of
those all-time high um areas, and I'm
talking about Bitcoin here, was in Q4 of
13, 17, and 21. And now obviously people
are saying, "Oh, it's basically quote Q4
of 2025. We're due for another, you
know, top, right? So maybe it now is a
top or sometime soon it'll be the top."
So the question is, does that apply in
this fourth four-year cycle or does it
not? And I wrote an essay called Long
Live the King where I studied two
charts. The first chart is um the Fed
funds rate and the amount of liquidity
created in dollar terms and then the
second chart is the credit impulse of
China like a a year-on-year change and
the overarching thesis is assume that
the technology for Bitcoin works and
knock on wood it has. So then what is
the value of Bitcoin? It's relative to
the thing that it's trying to improve
upon which is this fiat system and if
you've read the Satoshi white paper and
I encourage everyone who has not read
that paper to to read it and understand
what's uh what they are saying is that
Bitcoin is a reaction to money printing
and obviously the money printing that
you would react to would be that of
America because it's the leading
economic superpower controls the the
fiat money regime everybody else reacts
to that even China. And so then the
question is how has the price of money
evolved? How much money is there in the
world? How has that changed? Can we look
at the previous charts at the all-time
highs and see any sort of inflection
points? And throughout the essay, I
basically presented a scenario where,
you know, usually America and China are
doing the same thing. They might be, you
know, one or two years um apart in terms
of the the when they're printing money,
but they're both printing money at the
same time. 2009, China and the US both
printed money. China to rebuild
infrastructure, the United States to
bail out the banks. Obviously, that fed
into crypto and we get the rise to like
what is it 1300, 1400, whatever the the
high was on MTO in December of 2013.
Uh then there was the taper tantrum.
credit rolled over a bit in terms of the
amount of credit created in the US.
China did not follow up with another
mega stimulus after four years after the
2009 stimulus. And so that sort of broke
the crypto bull market, you know, 95% or
however much it went down back to the
2015 lows. And then the second cycle was
characterized by the US is actually
increasing the price of money and money
growth was actually falling, you know,
from the 2015 uh onwards. But China
embarked on another massive stimulus
program that was and if you know for
people in Asia, you remember the highs
in Shanghai composite in 2015.
Housing stocks um reinvigorated that a
new uh housing program to uh get stock
housing prices to go up in China. And
this money obviously made its way into
crypto and sort of reignited the bull
market in August 2015 when the POC did a
massive uh yuan devaluation versus the
dollar. And so obviously this bubble
preceded and then ultimately the Fed
hikes and the uh the decline in the
amount of bank and Fed credit uh popped
that bull market in 2017 and December
and then we went down again and then
obviously the last one was the COVID
stimulus checks. Obviously the United
States led um the world in terms of the
amount of stimulus that they gave out.
every other country followed in some
way, shape or form and that's how we got
into the 2021 high and then all the
governments were afraid of inflation and
so everyone started tightening uh rates
or communicating they were going to
start tightening rates in the end of
2021 and that's what popped that
particular all-time high. So as we come
to the 2025 story, what is that story?
That re story is really about the
reverse repo program. Starting in 2022,
Bad Girl Yellen, US Treasury Secretary
at the time, uh decided to engineer uh
an issuance schedule that essentially
drained this $2.5 trillion facility that
sat inert at the Fed, released this
liquidity into the markets. If you take
a look at a chart from sort of like
September of 2022
until uh now it's basically up only and
it mirrors the decline in the reverse
repo program. But that program has run
out. It's at zero right now. And so the
question is what's next? What's next?
And so
>> and what what is China doing?
>> So right now China is doing you know
it's flirting with deflation. They're
talking about housing program stimulus.
They're talking about some social
programs that they're going to reenact
for old people and and the children to
sort of give them more money to spend on
healthcare or whatever else. You have
Beijing actively going around to certain
industries and forcing people to shut
down factories to reduce the amount of
supply that they're generating. So,
they're reflating. Are they reflating as
much as they did in 2015 and 20 2009?
No. But it's exiting deflation. So, I'd
say it's um not really impacting much at
all, but it's not detracting from the
liquidity situation in the United
States. You know, Buffalo Bill Besson,
the US Treasury Secretary is talking
about uh bank credit growth. He's
they're talk Trump is talking about a
housing emergency to pump the housing
market to essentially take the trillions
of dollars trapped in home equity, allow
people to borrow against that and spend
on stuff. He's talking about tariff
funded stimulus checks. He's talking
about the Fed cutting rates, which
they're doing. Jerome Pow last night
talked about how they're going to stop
quantitative tightening. Now, he didn't
say he's going to restart money printing
via quantitative easing, but obviously
that's the next step. And so, the
rhetoric from politicians is positive
for the growth of liquidity and a
reduction in the price of money. And so,
based on their rhetoric, and obviously I
have no reason to doubt that they're
honest in what they're saying, they want
to pump pump the markets. I believe that
the credit cycle is going to extend.
We're going to get cheaper money in
terms of price and more plentiful,
especially in the United States, a
little bit more in China. And that tells
me that this 4-year cycle is uh not
going to happen. That will extend that.
How long? I don't know. But the
liquidity situation, if you look at the
forward statements from politicians and
money um policy makers, is that there
will be more fiat liquidity in the world
than less in the future and therefore
Bitcoin and crypto should benefit.
ETF.
Trading View. Trading View.
When you talk about liquidity, are we
talking about uh government spending,
central bank balance sheet. What exactly
are you looking at?
>> So those are all they're all you know
government spending, central bank
balance sheet. How much bank lending is
there? It's like is how many units of
fiat are there out in the world
>> and there's obviously various different
ways that you can create fiat and the
best thing about crypto is I don't have
to care where it comes from. I guess
know that if it gets created
>> then Bitcoin number go up but if you're
you know if you trade stocks right you
need to know okay which agency's
creating it what what sectors of the
economy are going to benefit from this
okay I should buy buy that stock right
and so it's a much diff more it's a
difficult proposition to pick stocks I
guess pick Bitcoin much easier
>> I've heard this um argument that says
you know money doesn't reach everybody
equally so the closer you are to the
source of money where it's created the
more you benefit. So it goes to right
now AI sector, maybe energy, maybe rare
earth. When does it get to Bitcoin?
>> It's already gotten to Bitcoin. Look at
the price performance over its history.
The money has been created. We know that
since 2009 and Bitcoin have been the
best performing asset in human history.
So I think it's, you know, we've proven
that there's a core there's a connection
to this phenomenon. Yes, maybe if you
bought Bitcoin yesterday, you're like,
"Oh, why isn't it at 200,000 yet?" I
think you need to be a bit more patient.
>> Well, it is true. People are talking
about year to date silver, gold, and a
lot of tech stock outperforming Bitcoin.
Well, we are sitting here talking about
Bitcoin being the best performing asset
in the world. And they're like, "No,
it's not." What do you say to these
people?
>> Snapshot the day in which you first
bought your your first Bitcoin. And
maybe it was yesterday, right? and you
say okay well um why hasn't it you know
is it going to outperform like well
what's your time horizon and you know I
don't know what everyone has a different
time horizon if you have a decent enough
time horizon maybe like let's measure in
the years sort of uh magnitude then I
believe Bitcoin would be the best
performing um asset better than gold
better than stocks better than real
estate now obviously if you pick one
particular stock and it goes up you know
200x right that's different I'm more
talking about broad indices
I think people have to be patient and
you know the history has proven that
there is a connection between the growth
in the money supply and and Bitcoin. So
if you believe that money supply will
continue to grow then Bitcoin has proven
itself to be the fastest horse in this
race. Yes, you could trade bonds, you
could trade stocks, you could trade real
estate, and it's up to your up to you,
but they're all going to go up. I just
think Bitcoin is going to go up the
most. Do you ever cash out and then
start buying stocks? Because maybe
during this period a certain stock
actually outperforms Bitcoin.
>> I'm not much of a stock trader. I only
own gold and silver mining ETFs. I don't
have time to try to pick stocks.
>> I see. Why is that? Is that a
characteristic in gold and silver that
you really like or what is it?
>> It's the same trade. It's just that
okay, I have a crypto bucket. So what's
my, you know, trady equity bucket? Okay.
What's the same trade? Same trade as
fiat
>> debasement, capital controls, financial
repression. What does well in the trady
world? Gold. What's been super
underowned? Gold miners and silver
miners have gotten trashed since 2011.
They're trading way well below where
they should given the meteoric rise of
gold and silver. So, I think those are,
you know, asymmetric things that I can
bet on. And obviously, they've done
very, very well this year. We've seen
some really crazy price action recently.
Big liquidations. Do you think it is
just how leverage work in a very thin
market? Does it reveal something that is
broken in the system? What happened?
>> Nothing is broken in the system. There
were rules. People didn't read the rules
and then they're surprised at the
result. Yeah. Automatic deleveraging. I
think now people actually understand
what that means. They didn't really
understand. You know, the first exchange
to offer that was, I think, Kabi back in
like 2014 is the first exchange I'm
automatically leveraging. It's been
around for 11 years. And yet, people are
surprised at how it works, right? Okay.
Every exchange had a different flavor on
their take on implementing this, but
again, this has been around since 2014.
If you don't understand how it works,
that's on you. Uh, second thing, cross
asset margin. A very technically
difficult problem to solve, which
requires a lot of trade-offs. There's no
perfect system. Every exchange has to
make a decision about how they're going
to mark these assets, how they're going
to handle liquidations and all these
sorts of things, right? Again, I don't
really use much leverage and I don't
trade on exchanges, but I imagine that
the documentation about how this system
works is all there. It's just nobody
decided to read it. It's been written
about in all the exchange literature. If
you didn't understand how that worked,
you shouldn't have been trading it in
the first place. And unfortunately,
people had to lose a lot of money to
learn these lessons. There's pissed-off
people. They lost a lot of money. I'd
say most of it is on the user,
unfortunately.
>> I I find this really interesting. So,
okay. Most of the comments I've seen on
Twitter or threads everywhere, they are
just pissed off at certain exchanges.
Break it down for these people. What
exactly happened? So, let's say if I
lose a lot of money that day, what
happened behind the scenes? Well,
there's certain traders who were had
leverage positions on, I guess, altcoin
contracts. There's a, you know,
volatility increase. Unfortunately, for
like 99.99% of all shitcoins, there is
no organic demand, which basically means
there's a group of market makers who are
paid either straight cash or via
incentives to post bidden offers on the
market, and they're profitm entities.
when either the tech breaks down like
API issues which were which were um
happening on exchanges due to high load
or the volatility increases obviously
Bitcoin drop was like 15% in a few
minutes they pull their quotes so all of
a sudden if you have this this shitcoin
that you were trading and you had some
leverage position on that has no
liquidity demand or supply other than
other market makers because there is
nobody else who trades this thing
because it's a piece of token then
you found out what it's really worth $75
80% down. That's what that thing is
worth. Um, and so unfortunately, people
had to discover this. Again, not the
exchanges fault. This is just what
happens when you trade something that
has no organic demand because it's a
piece of token, unfortunately.
>> So, can I say let's say a token dropped
80% and that should be the actual value
of the token at the time.
>> Uh, or you know, some dropped 80% and
rebounded quickly, right? you know,
things that I own like Pendle and
Athena, Ether, like, you know, these
things had,
>> you know, vicious liquidation candles
recovered, you know, decently
afterwards. There are some tokens that
will never recover because they are
piece of tokens with no clients who
spend no money and none of that money,
if they ever made any, it goes back to
the token holders. It's just it's Vibes.
People are trading on Vibes
>> and unfortunately,
>> Vibes will bankrupt you. There was this
YouTuber that compared prices of token
on uh Coinbase versus Binance and the
drop on Binance was a lot deeper and I
want to know why.
>> Uh I mean to the extent that I think
this is correct, there were some stable
coins that traded at uh very low prices.
Binance used those markets because they
were their own markets, the Binance
markets to mark certain traders
positions
>> and and they basically had to uh close
out their margin longs, I'm assuming,
right? And so then they just go and
smack down tokens, right? Until
everyone's account balances back in an
order to protect the exchange. And so
again, it's a it's a complicated
reflexivity of how you mark assets when
you trade a Bitcoin US dollar contract,
but you margin in another currency. How
do you do that?
>> And which mark price do you use? Do you
use the price on your own exchange to
mark the collateral or do you use an
external price of a bunch of other
exchanges to mark the collateral?
There's no right or wrong answer. It's
really as a policy choice and it's then
up to the chain to communicate the
policy choice
>> and then it's up to the trader to
understand the implications of that
particular policy choice. And one of the
implications was that because Binance
used marked assets based on prices on
the Binance exchange and Binance's
market was not as liquid as the global
market, then someone was able to push
the price down on some of these more
illquid collateral assets, forcing a
cascading of liquidations, which caused
those really deep liquidation wicks that
we saw in Binance and a lot of shitcoins
versus Coinbase, which doesn't have the
same micro structure of its markets and
didn't experience this. I want to ask
you about USDE. So that that day of
course on Binance it dropped to 0.65 I
think and um for a lot of Tread 5 people
texted me and they're like oh uh the
stable coin is not stable blah blah blah
and how would you explain to a person
that is not deep in crypto what actually
happened? So again, Binance has a USD
market. It's not that liquid versus
Curve, which is the most liquid place
where you can exchange USD for USDC, for
USDT, for other stables. Like Curve has
the most um liquidity. I can't I don't
know the numbers, but it's far and away
more liquid than Binance. If you take a
look at the USD price on Curve
>> versus Binance, you basically see it
barely moves on Curve and then Binance
has that massive dip down 65 cents and
then and then it recovers, right? So
this is just a
>> um one particular market not very
liquid. Somebody attacked that market by
dumping a bunch of US and it traded
lower.
>> If I if the global market had all fallen
down to 65 cents then we could say okay
what is the market worried about?
>> Okay what would if what would the market
be worried about at 65 cents? So because
of this massive liquidation event,
Athena's profit got capped and therefore
there are underhedged um as the market
keeps falling.
Unfortunately, I mean well not
unfortunately fortunately for Athena
that did not happen. Athena was
overcolateralized um throughout the
whole incident and actually made money
on some of its short positions. This is
I'm just re regurgitating what guy and
the Athena people put out on on X. And
so
>> it is improper to say that there was a
DEG. There was no DEG. The mint and
redeem functions of US worked perfectly
fine for all those who were authorized
to create and redeem US. Now, if that
function had been shut off or traders
were unable to essentially tender USD
and get back bitcoin or uh ethereum or
salana or UST, whatever you get back
when you redeem USDT, then I would say
yes, there was a dagging event.
>> The the the linkage between the
underlying assets and the ability for
authorized participants to create those
assets or redeem those assets that was
broken, therefore there was a deep
pecking of it. No, this is just Binance
has an illquid market. Somebody pushed
the price and obviously it generated
some adverse consequences, but the
Athena protocol is and was sound.
>> Now, it it just sounds like that day was
just a very short tragedy and a lot
happened within a very short period of
time, but people are not that concerned
about the crypto market long term.
This is not the start of a bare market.
>> I don't think so.
>> Last time we talked it was five months
ago and you famously said that, you
know, most of people's altcoins will not
go up in price no more, which was pretty
accurate in most cases, but we've seen
some of the coins go up like the
dexes, right? Uh Chinese meme coins for
example. But that was not quite the
altcoin season we were expecting.
>> I mean, everyone looks at the last cycle
and assumes that that will repeat and
every cycle is different. So, you know,
altcoin season in 2025 is means
something different than altcoin season
in 2020. That's just unfortunate fact of
markets. So,
>> so you think it actually happened or it
is happening.
>> I mean, hyperlas's done very well.
There's been there's definitely been
success stories in this cycle in terms
of altcoins. It's just, you know, they
weren't the you didn't succeed in the
same way you succeeded in 2020 and 21
when you we were all farming compound
and a dydx and unis swap and all these
other things, right? Different game than
today.
>> So, we have gone through an altcoin
season. Is that what you're saying?
>> We're in the altcoin season. People
people have made a lot of money on
certain altcoins. Unfortunately,
>> we are now better able to understand
that 99.99% of all these things are
zeros. And they have no clients. If they
have clients, they're not spending any
real money. They're just getting token
emissions. And then, you know, some
projects, unfortunately, have all this
money. They don't give it back to us as
token holders. And we're punishing them
all as they should be punished.
>> We are in mid October right now. Are you
still buying or are you taking profit?
>> Uh, we're fully invested. We're long.
So, I'm just sitting back and watching.
Have my pop my proverbial popcorn and
just watching.
>> When when it comes to taking profit,
should we sell it all at once? Should we
DCA out? What is your strategy? Either
buy cash%
Apple, Google PayP,
I think you should set a goal before you
get into you're trading, what is your
goal of investing in crypto? Is it okay,
I want to buy this particular good or is
it an outcome? I want to quit my job and
be a full-time corner. I don't
know. Whatever it is, right? So, the
first mistake people make is they don't
set a goal when they get into this. So,
what's your goal? Like, are what's my
goal? My goal is capital preservation,
not capital appreciation. So, I take way
less risk than somebody else. uh because
maybe their goal is capital appreciation
because they don't have enough capital
and then when they get to that point
then maybe they switch to preservation
mode. But you have to set your goal
first and then when you reach the goal
then you take the profit commencement
with you know the goal. But if you don't
set a goal, if you don't have any idea
why you're doing this or how long you
want to do it for, how much effort you
want to spend, then you know, you might
take profit at the wrong time or you
might never take profit at all or
>> that that's the so I don't think there's
a onesizefits-all
strategy for this. It really has to do
with what are your personal or firmwide
goals for getting into this crypto
ecosystem.
>> I want to know what your goal would look
like. Let's say I'm a 25year-old just
got into this market. I have 100k and I
want to retire at I don't know 10 mil.
Now what? Like do you
>> I think it should be more of an uh an
outcome based than cuz money is just a
tool. Is that the goal in and of itself?
There was something you wanted to do
when you got to that number whether it
was quit my job, buy a house, buy a car,
go travel, whatever it was, right? Well,
you thought you thought you could quit
your job, but no. Nah,
>> there's a point to making money if
you're going to do something with it,
where whatever that thing or activity
is. And so, I think you should
>> plan for that. And then obviously, how
do you want to make your money depends
on like how much time commitment, right?
Some people say, "Yeah, I'm willing to
be in the trenches 24/7,
>> have phone alarms on whenever whatever
happens. I get alerted. I don't care
about my sleep and all that sort." Okay,
cool. Be a crypto trader. use the
leverage, trade purpose, do all this
stuff. If you're willing to dedicate
yourself like that to your profession,
which is
>> day trading, if you're like, you know
what, I other things I want to do in my
life, maybe I have a full-time job, and
maybe this is just like an investment to
supplement my income, then you need to
take a little bit longer term view on
what you're you're buying. You need to
have a good understanding of the white
paper. What is your investing in? What
are the narratives? Like, what does this
look like? What do I think the world
looks like in, you know, a year and a
half, two years, whatever it is, right?
a longer time horizon so that you're not
sitting there trying to juke and jive in
the markets and getting chopped up and
liquidated and all those sorts of things
because you can't concentrate to the
level necessary to be successful as a
trader who uses leverage. So I think a
lot of the issue is that people have a
dream but they don't think about the
time that they want to invest to get
there. Like oh if I just do 100x
leverage I'm just going to you know 10x
my my stack every time I put a trade on.
of course.
>> And I and I didn't feel like, you know,
spending the many hours to read the
documentation about what I'm actually
trading, how this exchange works, and
then all of a sudden I lose everything
in 10 minutes. Um, because the exchange
worked exactly how they said it was
going to work.
>> And that's the unfortunate part. Now, I
know that the exchange execs
experiencing and dealing with these
customer support issues cannot say it
like that. I can't give a Um, and
I've been there before and you know this
is what unfortunately is has happened. I
don't think the exchanges are really at
fault here. It's really just um
customers do not have the proper
appreciation for the amount of time it
takes to be a good trader.
>> Do you see volatility and risk as the
same thing?
>> No. No. I mean volatility is one risk if
you use leverage or it's an asset if you
don't in certain circumstances. Risk is
there so many different types of risk.
smart contract risk, change getting hack
risk, all these sorts of things. So
again, volatility could be a good thing,
could be a bad thing, depends on what
you're trading.
>> So when a layman person sees Bitcoin,
they're like, "This is a risky asset."
Is this statement wrong?
>> Uh yes, it is wrong. Why is it risky? Is
it, "Oh, I wanted to put, you know, my
whole life savings in it and if the
thing goes down 10%, I can't pay my
mortgage or something like that, right?"
Yes, it is a risky asset because of your
outcome and how you're investing. If
you're saying, "Hey, I believe this is a
a call option on, you know, fiat
debasement,
>> then I love volatility. Make my option
more valuable. I love that. I have an
infinite duration. Give me more
volatility." So, really again, how why
are you investing in Bitcoin? What's
your time horizon? How much are you
willing to lose? Volatility is either an
asset or or could detract from the
performance of your portfolio. Earlier
you said you are now investing more
conservatively but in another interview
you said you identify early investments
exit within two to three years and you
aim for 10x to 100x returns
>> a lot
>> but but I'm also you know our checks are
50 to $100,000 and not very big if you
think about in a venture capital
perspective
>> if we lose 100% on every single one of
our you know VCves investors which we
Um, hats off to Asha and the team for
the amazing work they've been doing.
Then we would still make money as
Maelstrom because we have advisory, we
do other liquid trading. So it again,
it's a whole suite of uh trading
strategies that we employ. Um, the
riskiest stuff that we do on the VC
side, we deploy the least amount of
capital.
>> And obviously to make up for the fact
that we're not deploying that much
capital, we expect very very high
returns. And so that's how I sort of
calibrate things, which I don't give a
whether or not any of these
investments do well or not do well
because I'm not putting that much
capital on the line. But asymmetrically,
if they do really well, really well,
then great. Okay, I turned, you know,
50,000 into a million dollars. Hats off.
>> What would make you want to put down
that investment? Is it the founder or
the narrative? What is that one thing
you look for?
>> I don't look for anything. I don't look
at any investment. Um, Ashhat is a good
investor. I trust him. I sign everything
that that comes across my desk. I know
we look at, you know, team quality of
team founders. Uh obviously narrative,
time in the cycle. I'm more focused on
time in the cycle. Right.
>> Right now is at the right time in the
cycle. So for us at least, right? The
prices that are offered on good projects
are too expensive. And so we are not
investing right now very very much at
all. I don't even know. We've probably
done a handful of VC deals this year if
I can even remember. What would have to
happen for you to start again? market go
down 80% something like that then people
start getting religion in terms of price
and what we're offering the high quality
projects are coming in our strike zone
we have very strict limits on what we'll
pay doesn't matter how it doesn't matter
what we think of your project we will
only pay X and if you know that doesn't
work out that's fine we'll wait we're
patient
>> do you ever sell Bitcoin if you expect
the market to go down 80% do you sell it
and buy it back
>> we'll see what happens when you get
there what what are the other options
with my money what I want to do you know
I don't I I can't make that
determination right here
>> because there there are two
ways of trading Bitcoin that I've heard.
One says the Michael Sailor way is I
I'll always buy the top. I will not
sell. This is the most and the cheapest
you can buy like at this moment. And
then the other way is you can trade it
like four seasons. You know, you you
sell in summer, buy in winter. That way
you accumulate the most Bitcoin. Which
which one are you? I think it really
depends on your capital structure. Like
of course he doesn't care because we
always buy big. He's buying it through a
public company where he's issuing debt
to do it. Like there's a reason why he's
able to say these sorts of things. You
are not all Michael Sailor. There's only
one Michael Sailor and there's like one
micro strategy and you are not that. So
I don't think taking his advice in terms
of what he does at a company level,
which makes sense for the capital
structure he's engineered makes sense
for an individual investor. Yeah. Okay.
Maybe if you're only only investing like
a few basis points of your net worth,
like do you give a No. This is a
call option, right? You, you know, it'll
do well or it won't do well. And sure,
you're not really concerned about buying
or selling it. If this is 95% of your
net worth and you're trying to, you
know, do different things, then maybe
you'll sell some, buy a house or
whatever, buy some other good or service
or what have you, right? Because you've
done well, now you can use this capital
to achieve a certain life outcome.
>> But not everyone can time the market so
well. Of course.
>> So, so, so you are are you you are
saying that people should still enjoy
their life. It's not all about stacking
Bitcoin.
>> You you stack Bitcoin for a purpose.
What in everyone's purpose
>> is it for my purpose? I want to go
skiing, right? Okay. Am I going to
>> am I am I going to sacrifice my time on
the slopes to take more risk in crypto?
that. No way. I'm here to ski.
>> Oh my god. I love that. You also talked
about a generational collapse. What is
that?
>> So, I mean, I think we're going to
massive money printing all over the
world and sometime by the end of the
decade, we'll get a massive bare market
in everything. Crypto, stocks, property,
um, everything. Hopefully, there's no
war, but I think we're going to have a,
you know, a reset.
>> Why Why can't people just keep on
printing if that is what they're going
to do anyway?
>> They can. And then you know you will
find that you don't have a a head on
your shoulders after a while. there. So,
you know, at a certain point, society
says enough is enough and we're
unwilling to accept this and we're going
to depose you. And I mean, we're seeing
this in Nepal, uh, what other country I
guess for Madagascar, there's a popular
uprising. The youth are they're, you
know, they're educated, they have the
internet, they have AI, they read
history, they're like, "This is
This whole system is
bullshit." And the wheels are starting
to come off slowly, you know, in little
countries that, you know, the West
doesn't care about or maybe China
doesn't care about. But this this is the
trend, right? The young are like, "This
is This system that people
older than us have created, yet we're
the ones who are supposed to inherit
this. it. Let's let's have a new
system." Now, I don't know if it's the
new system is better or worse, but at
least it's not the same. And what is
insanity? It's doing the same thing over
again, expecting a different result. And
I think the youth of the world are done
doing the same thing expecting a
different result. And so they're going
to change it up. And the more money you
print, the faster you herald this this
change where those without financial
assets, crypto, stocks, real estate,
whatever, those the 99% of the world who
doesn't have enough financial assets to
escape the money printing say, "Well,
you. I'm not going to sit here as a
docile debt donkey. I'm going to get off
my ass and protest and depose the
government or whatever." And so I think
that's the unfortunate result when you
inflate away the money supply
>> and you think that's going to happen
everywhere in the world.
>> I think we're going to have, you know,
convulsion. Not to say that they'll be
successful in every part of the world,
but if we go by the little things that
we've seen so far, this is the trend.
The the nihilism of Gen Z. And it's
always the youth who are the most
invigorated proponents of any
revolution, whether successful or not.
They'll be the ones out in the street um
crying and dying. But you know we'll see
what sort of political systems emerge
out of that. But it's very difficult to
own financial assets in these times cuz
you know it's unpredictable.
>> Um I am not familiar with if this have
happened in the past. H has it happened
before like people go on the street
protest and somehow the financial system
just resets itself.
>> Uh I mean look at what happened in 1917
and you know so you know bullshiks in
Russia right? They had a whole SARS
system. The Buge was thrown out. You
know, if you change the system, there
are new people on top, new people on the
bottom. Obviously, the same similar
thing happened in 1949 in communist
China. You know, certain there were
certain winners in Mal China and a lot
of losers. Some very big recent examples
of what happens when you have a whole
disillusioned part of society fed up
with inflation and mismanagement. You
say, "Okay, we're just going to change
the system." Now, whether or not it's
better or worse, the system before is
kind of irrelevant. It's just change and
there are losers in this change.
>> Can I say that during the Trump's
administration at least the economy will
be good?
>> Good for who? Depends on what you mean
by good, right? You know, good as stocks
go up. Okay, good. Do you do you own
stocks? 90% of Americans don't own
enough stocks. So, but
>> yeah, that that's a fair point. That's a
fair point. Okay, maybe you break it
down for me. What would it look like
from your prediction?
>> I Bitcoin a million dollars. It's very
simple. Like everything's up. the S&P
10,000 NASDAQ 50,000 house you know
median house prices 75 $750,000 yeah I
mean this is his goal if you listen to
what he says what his US treasur uh
secretary says Buffalo Bill Besson
they're very clear we want to run the
economy high we want to have high growth
to delever the American balance sheet
and obviously that entails inflation
they want the markets to go up Trump
thinks that the stock market and the
crypto market are his report card how
well is he doing What's the S&P? What's
Bitcoin at? What's the Trump memecoin
at? That's what he cares about, for good
or for bad, whatever. And so he believes
that if he can generate paper wealth in
the financial markets, that will lead
to, you know, a stronger America and
whatever that means to him and his
supporters. So believe him, he's going
to do whatever it takes to print the
money to get there. And you know,
similar in China, right? China believes
that the stock market, or at least
they're trying to tell people the stock
market as it rises, that means that
we're doing better. as the government.
And so you should you should buy stocks
because you believe that the Chinese
Communist Party is going to deliver on
all these things you retail investor. So
again, it's all every government whether
or not they're communist or capitalist
is the same. They do different things to
juice the markets. But I think you know
a lot of governments view the stock
market as their their report card.
>> Since we're talking about US US debt and
all that, I want to ask you about stable
coins. So, um I think in one of your
interviews with Bankless in May, you
were talking about how you know stable
coin um so basically you were saying
that Genius Act forces stable coin
issuers to buy short-term T bills and
that means uh it quietly shifts the real
power from the Fed to the US Treasury.
Is that right?
>> Yeah. So as there is this cohort of
folks to earn money they need to buy
treasuries.
>> Mhm.
>> They can only buy that's all they can
buy. They got dollars. What else? What
can you buy? The only thing risk-free
asset you can buy is a US treasury in
nominal terms. So Bessin can say, "Okay,
well, I now control the short end of the
curve because I can issue my T bills at
whatever rate I want and I know that
this massive uh stable coin issuer crowd
has to buy whatever I'm selling at
whatever price
>> I'm selling it at because they have no
other option because if they want to
earn revenue, they need to earn they
need to invest in an income producing
asset that is a US Treasury bill." And
so that's how he neuters the Fed because
now the Fed funds rate doesn't matter.
uh it's whatever best it wants to put
short-term rates at via his T bill
issuance.
>> Is this just a prediction or is it
happening?
>> This is just a prediction. There's the
the stable coin market isn't big enough
yet. Obviously, Tether is massive at
like the 19th largest holder of of debt.
But I think as you know we get to
trillions of dollars worth of stable
coins in circulation then the largest
holders of T bills will become very um
powerful and there'll be a cohort to be
gone after by the Treasury in terms of
hey I've got these T bills maybe Fed
funds is at 2% but best needs it at
once. Okay, I'm going to give you 1%.
And they're going to say okay cool I
have no other option sure give it to me.
So then we're watching a world where you
know government spending now becomes the
main driver of the market. Not that
>> it already has been the government
spending um central bank balance sheets
and bank credit growth. Every country
and government does things a bit
differently but those are the three main
ways in which fiat gets created and so
that's why we should monitor it as
crypto investors.
>> Okay. Then let's talk about Google and
what they're doing with their sable
coin. So, and they came up with this
thing that's called the agent payment
protocol. That means, you know, AI
agents can literally just pay each other
crypto tokens. So, do you think we're
seeing a world or we're moving towards a
world where machine to-achine
transaction is going to happen and
without us even knowing? Of course,
because there are different agents who
have to buy and sell things on the
internet and the thing that they have to
buy and sell the the most critical thing
they have to buy and sell are uh
intelligence. So tokens, right? I think
at some point there's going to be some
sort of connection between a
cryptographic blockchain and inference
on AI like okay, I want to run this chat
GPT. Okay, my request uses so many
tokens and obviously I'm paying for them
implicitly via my subscription. But what
if a government says, "Okay, well, we
need to tax these robots and these AIs
because we need to fund social programs
for these humans who don't have work."
The easiest way it's going to happen is
I'm going to put a tax on tokens. So
every time me as a customer generate
some sort of request or an agent's doing
something on my behalf, it's using
intelligence spending tokens, it has to
pay some tax somehow to to the
government. So, I think there's
definitely going to be cryptographic
payments. Maybe it's in Bitcoin. Maybe
it's some other uh blockchain that'll be
happening between AI agents and then us
as well as the the end user of some of
these things.
>> Why do you say Bitcoin?
>> Because it's the most proven form of
electronic money. Everyone uses it. It's
got the highest market cap. You know, if
you if you're an Asian who just, you
know, spawned into existence and you're
like, "Okay, well, I have to use this
money thing to get what I need." Are you
going to use a new form of money? maybe
some newly created new shitcoin or you
going to use, you know, the OG Bitcoin?
I would think you're going to use
Bitcoin because again, you want to
preserve, you know, your purchasing
power.
>> And you've probably been asked this a
hundred times about quantum computers,
but what is your thought?
>> I think that we have a known possible
vector of, you know, bad things
happening to Bitcoin. They're very smart
individuals who are much smarter than me
who probably have a lot more salient and
points on why quantum is a threat and
why it's not a threat. I'm not in the
weeds on that. I'll defer to people who
are much smarter than me to to talk
about that. But the good thing is we
know it's a risk.
>> There's a lot of cross talk in terms of
whether or not what is being built on
the quantum side is actually scaling
towards being able to break encryption
>> and other people saying no, it's so far
away you don't need to worry about this.
So I I don't know. I can't make heads or
tails of it. So that I'm not I'm not
particularly worried about it.
>> You're still skiing, so you're not too
worried.
>> Well, since we're talking about skiing,
you've compared skiing to trading. What
is this? What is What did you say again?
>> You said you overink, then you are going
to crash. Something like that.
>> I mean, I relaxed. So again, choose your
trading strategy that makes sense. I
would not be able to ski all day if I
was trying to, you know, ek out my
living leverage trading in crypto. Not
to say that's a bad thing to do, but
it's just a different way of approaching
things.
>> You seem very chill and relaxed right
now, but I would assume back in the days
it was very chaotic for you, you know,
running companies, trading crypto and
all that. What was it like? I mean, yes,
running an exchange obviously a lot more
work, but the good thing about an
exchange is if you structure correctly,
you should never lose money. And so, we
love volatility. Every, you know, things
like, you know, last weekend happened
and, you know, we've had similar
situations back in the day when when
BitMX was more relevant. Again, we made
a lot of money. Of course, you always
are trying to figure out new policies to
prevent um people from making bad
mistakes. And maybe this is, you know,
my own failings like I'm about bit more
of a market purist than maybe some of
the other exchange CEOs. And you know,
obviously there are certain times in
which you should relax these constraints
and uh give money to users who don't
otherwise deserve it. But I think at the
end of the day, if you build an exchange
correctly and put the proper uh risk
metrics in place in the exchange, it's
actually not that stressful of a job.
It's not the market movements that
generates the the stress of of running
an exchange because again you've
protected yourself. That's why all these
things exist is to protect the exchange
so that no matter what happens in the
market, you know, it's always open. You
can always trade and all uh and you know
make or lose money.
>> I love that you make it sound so easy.
But then you also said before that you
were also the customer support back in
the day.
>> Yeah. You know the early
Right. But then you make it sound so
easy right now.
>> We had our we had our stressful times.
But again, we weren't stressed about the
market moving which is I think
unfortunately a lot of exchange people
have created business models where they
need the price of this go to go up or
they need certain things to happen in
the market and when it doesn't happen
then they sur suffer adverse
consequences like you know FTX right Sam
Bank had to have the market go up and
when it stopped going up then he went
out of business. So that becomes
stressful.
We didn't have that kind of stress that
a bit we built, you know, while it still
runs a very good piece of tech that
mitigates a lot of these issues.
>> I see. I see. Um, can we spend the last
5 minutes of our conversation talking
about how you actually your journey
into, you know, the whole exchange game
and
um, what was it like? You spent half of
your life in Asia, I think.
>> Yes. I moved out here in 2008.
Uh, I wanted to be where the action was
and I studied Chinese in school. Then I
went to Hong Kong to live and work after
I graduated and then I never really left
the region.
>> Wait, so one day you're just like, I
want to study Chinese.
>> I studied Chinese in university cuz I
wanted to move to China.
>> Really?
>> Yeah.
>> What was it? Was it a movie? Was it a
person, a friend? Why? No, I I just
wanted to be economically
>> I didn't want to work my whole life in
the US structure and you know just be
one of other team millions of people in
New York City. I'd rather go somewhere
more fun like Asia.
>> So you grew up in New York?
>> Uh Buffalo, New York. It's a small city
but eight hours from New York than
Canada.
>> And I want to move to China. I want to
let's learn some Chinese.
>> Chinese.
>> Wow. And then what? You just moved here
after you graduated college?
>> Ever? Yeah. Found a job in Hong Kong and
then moved to Hong Kong after I
graduated.
>> And that was the first time you have
ever been to Asia.
>> No, I did I went I did study abroad and
I worked this summer in Asia as well. So
>> would you ever move back?
>> Um I mean China is different. I think
there's other places in Asia that I
like. I mean I ski in Japan so more in
Japan than anywhere else probably. I
love that you assume I said China. I was
talking about Buffalo, but
>> Oh, no.
>> Right. Well, why?
>> I would rather move to tier three
Chinese city than move back to Buffalo,
New York.
>> Really? Why?
>> You know, I I find it be more
interesting than going back to where
you're from. But I think that's everyone
could probably say the same thing,
right? You your hometown, you'd rather
go somewhere else and be where you're
from.
>> But you have been here for a long time.
>> Yeah.
You don't miss home. This is home.
>> This is home.
>> Interesting. Interesting. What? Well,
name a few things that you know, Asia is
better than us.
>> Food. I mean, I think you know, Asian
people are not going to suffer bad food
at all price levels, right? So,
>> true, true, true.
>> Especially like Singapore, you go to a
hawker center, it's super cheap. Or you
can go to, you know, super high-end uh
stuff. travel. There's so many different
climates, cold, hot, tropical,
subtropical, whatever, all across
region. Lots of different cultures. And
then if you think about economically,
this has been the center of the world
pretty much since human existence. It's
only been the last 500 years when it's
changed. And obviously things are
swinging back in sort of the Eurasian
direction going forward. So I think, you
know, this is the place to be.
>> I love talking to you. This was this was
great.
>> Thank you so much for your time.